torontopolice.on.ca 2004-06-10

# Toronto Police Service :: To Serve and Protect

Privacy and Security

The Toronto Police Service is committed to protecting the privacy of any personal information you may provide when visiting our Web site. Part of that commitment is to explain what information may be collected why, how it will be used and who may have access to it. Our practices have been designed to ensure compliance with the privacy provisions of the Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act. 

This privacy statement applies to interactions with the Toronto Police Service Web server. It does not apply to any other Web site. Following is an overview of our Web site practices. 

Personal Information

When you visit the Toronto Police Service web site, you do so anonymously - there is no need to tell us who you are. If you direct an enquiry to a unit, we will ask you to provide your name and mailing address or e-mail address for the purpose of responding to your enquiry. Only those who "need to know" will have access to the personal information provided. 

"Opt-in" Emails: Users may "opt-in" to receive site notifications, newsletters or other information via email. Users may remove themselves from such services at their discretion. Any email sent to an "opt-in" list will include directions for how a user may remove him or herself from the list, or a URL where the user may find such directions. 

Logging and Cookies

The Toronto Police Service will track the domains from which people visit our site and analyze this data for trends and statistics. 

Our logging is passive and is not used to maintain any information on site visitors. Logged information is recorded in non-identifiable form and is used only by Toronto Police Service staff. 

Cookies: The Toronto Police Service employs "cookies" to provide a user with tailored information. A cookie is a small piece of information our server asks your browser to store and give back to the server verbatim at a later time. Much like a dry-cleaning ticket is used to make sure you get the same clothes back when you visit, a cookie is used to make sure you get the same tailored information back when you visit. On it's own, the dry-cleaning ticket, or cookie doesn't contain any personally identifiable information, and doesn't have any use other than to relate to a previous transaction. Our cookies do not store any personal information about you, nor are they able to access any information on your computer. 

Comments?

We welcome any comments and suggestions about this site. Please contact us at webmaster(at)torontopolice.on.ca.
